MARIUS SOMMERFELD, MSc.

Copenhagen, Denmark (+49) 15786925882 | m.96.sommerfeld@gmail.com LinkedIn / Personal Website

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a MSc Data Science student particularly interested in the fields of Signal & Image processing, Computer Vision and Robotics. I participated in different research projects, and I am interested to do my Master Thesis in one of these fields. In my work and projects as well as my free time I like to learn new things and are attracted by steep learning curves.

EDUCATION

MAASTRICHT UNIVERSITY MAASTRICHT, NETHERLANDS

MSc Data Science for Decision Making (current GPA 9.13 / 10)

09. 2020 - PRESENT

- Research Project: Disentangling cell mixtures in cancer from omics data and images
- Research Project: Particle Track Reconstruction from VELOPIX Detector Data
- Relevant Coursework: Natural Language Processing, Computer Vision, Data Mining,
 Signal and Image processing, Advance Concepts in Machine Learning

MAASTRICHT UNIVERSITY MAASTRICHT, NETHERLANDS

BSc Econometrics and Operations Research, Cum Laude (GPA 8.19 / 10)

09.2016 - 08.2019

- BSc Thesis: Impact of delay allowance in freight transportation network design
- Relevant Coursework: Statistics, Econometric Methods, Operations Research, Finance, Economics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IVC INDEPENDENT VALUATION & CONSULTING AG. WPG.

ESSEN, GERMANY

Research Analyst Intern / Work Student

06.2020 - 08.2021

- Planning and setup of a Database holding financial data, delivered robust system
- Development of automatics programs filling the Database, setup and control of numerous processes
- Development of a valuation dashboard based on the database, speeding up the valuation workflow of the consultants 10-fold

HSBC GERMANY

DÜSSELDORF, GERMANY

Intern in Equity Derivatives trading

08.2019 - 01.2020

- Analysis of financial markets to deliver trading insights, supported trading decisions
- Creation of periodical trading reports, delivered historical overview of the market
- Development of a trading simulation to analyzing various products, resulted in multiple profitable trades

LANGUAGES

German (Native); **English** (Advanced); **Italian** (Intermediate)

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCES

Erasmus Exchange – IT University of Copenhagen

09.2021 - PRESENT

• Courses: Advanced Robotics, Modern Artificial Intelligence, Danish

Erasmus Exchange - University Luigi Bocconi

09. 2018 - 01. 2019

 Courses: Theoretical Computer Science, Introduction to Blockchain, Political Economics, Experimental Economics, Italian

SKILLS

Strong: Python (Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn), MySQL, Git, Excel, Refinitiv/Reuters EIKON, Capital IQ

Medium: Keras, Pytorch, Tensoflow, MATLAB, JAVA, HTML, CSS, C++, R Non IT: Self-Responsible, Trustworthy, Ambitious, Team Player, Social